Divya Kothandaraman

Email Google Scholar Website GitHub Twitter

Research Interests:

My research interests are in the broad areas of computer vision and deep learning. Specifically, my current/ past research has focused on the following:

Generative AI and Multi-modality: View synthesis, Image and video personalization

Computer vision: Domain adaptation, Video action recognition

I look forward to contributing and gaining experience in diverse areas of AI including computer vision, deep learning, generative AI, multimodal learning and robotics.

Education:

University of Maryland College Park, USA - PhD in Computer Science (Aug 2020 - Aug 2024)

Advisor: Prof. Dinesh Manocha

Committee: Prof. Ming Lin, Prof. Tianyi Zhou, Prof. Jia-Bin Huang

Indian Institute of Technology Madras, Chennai, India - Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering & Master of Technology in Data Sciences (Jul 2015 - Jul 2020)

Publications:

- [14] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Tianyi Zhou, Ming Lin, Dinesh Manocha. "HawkI: Homography and Mutual Information Guidance for 3D-free Single Image to Aerial View". (Under Review) Paper
- [13] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Sumit Shekhar, Balaji Vasan Srinivasan, Dinesh Manocha. "ImPoster: Text and Frequency Guidance for Subject-Driven Action Personalization using Diffusion Models". (Under Review)
- [12] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Kihyuk Sohn, Ruben Villegas, Paul Voigtlaender, Dinesh Manocha, Mohammad Babaeizadeh. "Text Prompting for Multi-Concept Video Customization by Autoregressive Generation". AI for Content Creation (AI4CC) Workshop at Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2024
- [11] Ruiqi Xian, Xijun Wang, **Divya Kothandaraman**, Dinesh Manocha. "PMI Sampler: Patch similarity guided frame selection for Aerial Action Recognition". IEEE/ CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2024 <u>Paper</u>
- [10] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Tianyi Zhou, Ming Lin, Dinesh Manocha. "Aerial Diffusion: Text Guided Ground-to-Aerial View Translation from a Single Image using Diffusion Models". Siggraph Asia 2023 (Conference Proceedings Technical Communications, 8 mins Oral) <u>Paper</u>
- [9] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Ming Lin, Dinesh Manocha. "DifFAR: Differentiable Frequency-based Disentanglement for Aerial Video Activity Recognition". IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2023 Paper

- [8] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Sumit Shekhar, Abhilasha Sancheti, Manoj Ghuhan, Tripti Shukla, Dinesh Manocha. "DistillAdapt: Source Free Active Visual Domain Adaptation". IEEE/ CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2023 <u>Paper</u>
- [7] James Mullen, **Divya Kothandaraman**, Aniket Bera, Dinesh Manocha. "Placing Human Animations into 3D Scenes by Learning Interaction and Geometry-Driven Keyframes". IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2023 <u>Paper</u>
- [6] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Tianrui Guan, Xijun Wang, Sean Hu, Ming Lin, Dinesh Manocha. "FAR: Fourier Disentangled Space Time Attention for UAV Activity Recognition". European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2022 <u>Paper</u>
- [5] Tianrui Guan, **Divya Kothandaraman**, Rohan Chandra, Dinesh Manocha. "GANav: Group-wise Attention Network for Classifying Navigable Regions in Unstructured Outdoor Environments". IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) 2022 and IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2022. <u>Project Page</u>
- [4] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Rohan Chandra, Dinesh Manocha. "SS-SFDA: Self-Supervised Source Free Domain Adaptation for Road Segmentation in Hazardous Environments". IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision Workshops (ICCV-W) 2021 (Oral). Project Page
- [3] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Rohan Chandra, Dinesh Manocha. "BoMuDA: Boundless Multi-Source Domain Adaptive Segmentation in Unconstrained Environments". IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision Workshops (ICCV-W) 2021 <u>Project Page</u>
- [2] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Athira Nambiar, Anurag Mittal. "Domain Adaptive Knowledge Distillation for Driving Scene Semantic Segmentation", IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications in Computer Vision Workshops (WACV-W) 2021 <u>Paper Slides</u>
- [1] Varun Sundar, Sumanth Hegde, **Divya Kothandaraman**, Kaushik Mitra. "Deep Atrous Guided Filter for Image Restoration in Under Display Cameras". European Conference on Computer Vision Workshops (ECCV-W) 2020 <u>Paper</u>

Patents:

- [2] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Kuldeep Kulkarni, Sumit Shekhar, Balaji Vasan Srinivasan, Dinesh Manocha. "ImPoster: Frequency Guidance for Subject Driven Action Transfer from Image using Diffusion Models". (US Patent with Adobe Research under review).
- [1] **Divya Kothandaraman**, Sumit Shekhar, Abhilasha Sancheti, Manoj Ghuhan, Tripti Shukla. "Systems and Methods for Active Domain Adaptation". US Patent App. 17/648,482, 2023.

Professional Experience

Research Intern, Google DeepMind (Brain) Mountain View, California, May 2023 - Aug 2023

• Video Personalization with Mohammad Babaeizadeh, Kihyuk Sohn and Ruben Villegas; paper under review.

Research Intern, Adobe Research

Remote (India), May 2022 - Aug 2022

• Exemplar Image Animation with Kuldeep Kulkarni; paper under review.

Research Intern, Adobe Research

Remote (India), May 2021 - Aug 2021

• Domain Adaptation with Sumit Shekhar. Paper published at WACV 2023.

Research Intern, Intel

Remote (India), Aug 2020 - Jan 2021

• Incremental Few-shot Object Detection in Unstructured Traffic Environments

RnD intern, Samsung Research Institute

Bangalore, India May 2018 - July 2018

• Advanced technologies lab, Researched single-view 3D reconstruction for AR

Research Intern, Indian Institute of Science Bangalore

Advisor: Prof. Venu Madhav

Bangalore, India May-Jul '17&Dec '17

• Multi-view 3D reconstruction and motion averaging for Iterative Closest Point Algorithm

Talks:

• [Invited Talk, Mar 2024] 3D-free Text Controlled Aerial-View Synthesis from a Single Image using Diffusion Models, High-Beams Seminars, University College London (UCL)

- [Contributed Talk, Dec 2023] Aerial Diffusion: Text Guided Ground to Aerial View Synthesis using Diffusion Models, SIGGRAPH Asia 2023
- [Contributed Talk, Jan 2023] SALAD: Source-free Active Label Agnostic Domain Adaptation, WACV 2023
- [Contributed Talk, Oct 2021] SS-SFDA: Self-Supervised Source Free Domain Adaptation for Road Segmentation in Hazardous Weather Conditions, ICCV-W 2021

Professional service:

- Reviewer: TIP, TPAMI, IEEE-RAL, CVPR '22, ECCV '22, WACV '23, AAAI '23, BADUE IROS '23, CVPR '23, ICCV '23, AAAI '24, WACV '24, ICRA '24, CVPR '24
- Committee member, UMD CS Graduate School Applications 2021, 2022, 2023
- GradCo CS Peer Mentor, UMD (Spring 2022, Fall 2022)

Awards and Scholastic Achievements:

- ICSSA Travel grant award of \$270 from UMD for SIGGRAPH Asia 2023
- Goldhaber Travel grant award of \$600 from UMD for SIGGRAPH Asia 2023
- Dean's Fellowship 2020, University of Maryland College Park
- Secured All India Rank 1065 in Joint Entrance Exam Advanced 2015, taken by 1.3 million students (99.92 percentile).
- Qualified for INChO (Indian National Chemistry Olympiad) 2015, state top 1% in NSEP (physics olympiad) and NSEC (chemistry olympiad).

Teaching Experience:

Jul-Nov 2019: Teaching Assistant for the course EE4708, Data Analytics Laboratory, IIT Madras Jan -May 2020: Teaching Assistant for EE1101 Signals and Systems, IIT Madras